applynow.net.au 2014-11-21

# Find Jobs in Australia - ApplyNow.com.au Job Search Site

At applynow.com.au, we understand how important privacy is and we abide by the [Privacy Act 1998](http://www.comlaw.gov.au/comlaw/Legislation/ActCompilation1.nsf/0/19CF4540B05BECE4CA25736E00189940?OpenDocument). This document discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices, as we value our users, and recognize their rights to keep information private.

### Collecting Information on applynow.com.au and applynow.net.au Visitors

applynow.com.au and applynow.net.au collects information on our site visitors collectively including which sections of the site are most frequently visited, how often and for how long. This data is always used as aggregated, non-personal information to better our services by monitoring which parts of on the site which are visited the most. This information may be shared with applynow.com.au partners to provide them with an overview of how applynow.com.au visitors use the site. This is done for the purposes of providing you with the best online career management services.

### Registering as a Jobseeker

As part of registering with applynow.com.au and applynow.net.au, we collect personal information about you in order for you to take full advantage of applynow.com.au’s services. To do this it may be necessary for you to provide additional information to applynow.com.au as detailed below. Registering with us is completely optional. However, registration for jobseeker services allows you to take advantage of more of the tools and resources that assist you in finding a job. Registration includes submitting your email address. You may access this information at any time by clicking “Change Details” on the “my account” screen when you’ve logged onto applynow.com.au as a Jobseeker.

### Job Notifications

Job Notifications is an optional service. applynow.com.au and applynow.net.au requests that you provide information relating to your employment preferences as well as your email address so that we may notify you via email of jobs specific to your needs. Users can modify or delete their Job Notifications profiles at any time by going to the [Jobseeker](http://applynow.com.au/my_saved_searches.php) area of the site, .

### Online Applications

Making an online application to a job advertisement on applynow.com.au and applynow.net.au is a free and optional service that does not require registration. Job applications require you to complete mandatory fields (first name, last name, phone and email) so that the advertiser can identify and contact you. Your application, including attachments and cover letters, are forwarded directly on to the third party advertiser. This information may also be disclosed to applynow.com.au’s service providers and contractors from time to time who assist us to deliver our products and services.

By applying to a position advertised on applynow.com.au you are requesting that applynow.com.au pass the information to the Advertiser as a part of your application.

Additionally, you have the right to request your personal information direct from [Advertisers](http://applynow.com.au/rates.php) on applynow.com.au.

### Collecting Information on applynow.com.au and applynow.net.au Visitors

applynow.com.au collects information that is necessary for the function of the site activities.

When you visit applynow.com.au we may make a record of your visit and log some or all of the following information for statistical, maintenance or improvement purposes:

  * Your service or internet provider (IP) address – information is gathered in summation only and cannot be traced to an individual user;
  * The address of the referring site (if any);
  * The date and time of your visit;
  * Your top level domain name (for example, .org.au, .gov.au, .com.au etc);
  * The address of the page that is accessed and the documents downloaded;
  * The type of browser you used.
  * We also collect personal information when you complete the contact form or when you subscribe to our online newsletter. applynow.com.au utilises this information to improve and enhance our services by monitoring the areas on the site which are most popular to you. This non-personal information may be shared with applynow.com.au partners to provide them with an overview of how visitors use applynow.com.au

### Email Communications from applynow.com.au and applynow.net.au

applynow.com.au and applynow.net.au also provides you with selected information about new jobs listed on the site, as well as info on career-related topics in our email newsletter. This free service is sent to registered users and provides the option of opting out of receiving these by clicking the “unsubscribe” link on emails sent.

### Storage & Security of Personal Information

  * applynow.com.au and applynow.net.au has implemented appropriate physical, electronic and managerial security procedures in order to protect personal information from loss, misuse, alteration or destruction.
  * applynow.com.au and applynow.net.au regularly reviews security and encryption technologies and will strive to protect information to the fullest extent possible.
  * applynow.com.au allows you to access your information at any time to keep it accurate and up to date. Any information which we hold for you is stored on secure servers.
  * Our employees and the contractors who provide services related to our information systems are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by applynow.com.au.
  * applynow.com.au will not be held responsible for events arising from unauthorised access of your personal information.

### applynow.com.au Partners & Advertisers

applynow.com.au provides links and passes online application to third party sites. The use of your information by these third party sites is not within the control of applynow.com.au and we cannot accept responsibility for the conduct of these companies. Advertisers who place job ads on applynow.com.au are asked to comply with Australian federal privacy policy with regard to their own information handling practices. You may also directly contact advertisers to request access to any personal information that you have sent as part of an application.

### Use of Cookies

A cookie is a small piece of text that is placed within the memory of a computer and can be later retrieved by web page servers. applynow.com.au uses cookies to enhance your interaction and convenience with its website and does not use cookies to record any personal information.

### Transborder Data Flows

applynow.com.au principally deals with Australian companies, though sometimes, we may transfer information to persons outside Australia (e.g. an employer, or a contractor who supplies services to applynow.com.au). By giving us your personal information, you consent to such disclosures. In addition, we believe that the recipients of such information are subject to a law, binding scheme or contract which effectively upholds principles for fair handling of the information that are substantially similar to the National Privacy Principles.

### Privacy & Site Changes

applynow.com.au may review and update its privacy statement in the future if required. Revised versions will be updated on the website. The website itself will be updated from time to time, to ensure the best service to all jobseekers and advertisers.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, or have feedback to help improve applynow.com.au you can contact us via email, or post:

Employment Office Australia Pty Ltd trading as applynow.com.au  
**ABN :** 18 129 212 602  
**Trading Address:** Unit 1, 205 Moggill Road, Taringa, Queensland, 4068, Australia

**Tel:** (07) 3168 0090  
**Post:** applynow.com.au  
Po Box 1670   
Milton Qld 4064

For more information about privacy issues in Australia, please visit the Australian Federal Privacy Commissioners [website](http://www.privacy.gov.au/).
